A Guide to the Gertrude E. Perlmann papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA189
Rockefeller Archive Center
Gertrude E. Perlmann papers, Rockefeller University Faculty
1935-1974
Rockefeller Archive Center
Perlmann, Gertrude E.
Rockefeller University
Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
FA189
37.48 Cubic Feet 77 boxes and 2 packages
Biographical/Historical note
Gertrude Erika Perlmann, 1912-1974, at the RU (formerly RIMR) from 1947-1974. An authority in the field of protein chemistry. In 1960 she spent 6 months as a visiting professor at the Weizmann Institute, Rehovoth, Israel in Professor Ephraim Katchalski's laboratory. From 1960-1963 she served as National Vice-President of Iota Sigma Pi. In 1965 she received the Garvan Award from the American Chemical Society for her "distinguished service to chemistry". She was cited for her research on the structure of pepsin, an enzyme that speeds food digestion and for demonstrating the chemical structure of pepsin and its ability to break down food. She showed how the atoms are arranged in the pepsin molecule and the structural changes that occur when pepsinogen, the inactive form of pepsin, is activated. She did much investigative work on phosvitin. In 1970 she was coeditor with Laszlo Lorand of Methods in Enzymology, Volume XIX, Proteolytic Enzymes.
Biographical note
1912 Born April 20 Reichenberg, Czechoslovakia
1936 Sc D. German University of Prague (chemistry and physics)
1937-1939 Copenhagen, Biological Institute of the Carlsberg Foundation with Fritz Lipmann; at the Carlsberg Laboratory, Chemical Dept. with Professor K. Linderstrøm-Lang
1938 Prague, Czechoslovakian Public Health Institute (5 months June-Oct)
1939-1941 Research Assistant, Harvard Medical School, (Physical Chemistry), Boston
1941-1946 Research Fellow, Massachusetts General Hospital/Harvard Medical School, Boston
1945 USA naturalization
1946 RI Guest Investigator (Commonwealth Fund Fellowship)
1947 RI Research Associate
1951 RI Assistant Professor
1958 RI Associate Professor
1960 Visiting Professor, Weizmann Institute, Rehovoth, Israel (6 months)
1973 RU Professor
1974 Died September 9 New York Hospital; New York, N.Y.; Cremated; Memorial service at Frank E. Campbell Funeral Parlor. Speakers: Jules Hirsch, Laszlo Lorand
1965 Garvan Award
RU Committees
1951-1952 Secretary, Program Committee/RI staff meetings
1967-1969 RU Faculty Committee/Lectures
1967-1970 Board of Directors/RU Faculty and Students' Club
Served
1962-1964 Joint Committee on Biochemical Nomenclature of ASBC (American Society of Biological Chemists) and AIN (American Institute of Nutrition) (Chairman 1964/65)
1963-1966 Iota Sigma Pi National Vice-President; 1965-1966 Chairman, Awards Committee of Iota Sigma Pi, 1972 Award Committee of Iota Sigma Pi
1970 Coeditor with L. Lorand of Methods in Enzymology, Volume XIX, Proteolytic Enzymes
1973 Advisory Board for new edition of Handbook of Biochemistry and Molecular Biology
Member of: American Association of University Professors, American Chemical Society (1965, 1972 Nominating Committee, Division of Biological Chemistry), American Society of Biological Chemists Biophysical Society, British Biochemical Society, Harvey Society, Iota Sigma Pi (Honorary after 1969), Israel Biochemical Society, Sigma Xi (Treasurer 1969-1970)
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be closed to research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be closed to researchers at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/Head of Reference.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The papers of Gertrude Erika Perlmann were deposited by Dr. Peter Perlmann.
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 450 P422
Conditions Governing Access note
This collection is open for research.
Chemistry; Biochemistry; Life sciences; Enzymes; Pepsin; Pepsinogen; Amino acids; Medicine, Preventive; Medical sciences; Medical research; Perlmann, Gertrude E.; Rockefeller University; Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
- Bibliography and biographical articles (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bibliography
  - The Iotan 23, 1964; 5 items
  - Iotan Newsletter, 1973 September 24
  - Who Was Who (photocopy) 6, 1974-1976; 321 items and galley proof
- Correspondence (Personal), 1927 September 7 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Arrangement note
  Arranged in chronological order.
  - Birth certificate transcripts., 1933 September 14
    Scope and Contents
    (one German, one English)
  - Diploma, 1933 October 5
    (foreign language)
  - Diploma, 1936 November 14
  - ScD degree from German University of Prague, 1937 November 6
  - Sorensen and K. Linderstrøm-Lang letter of recommendation in German, 1938 February 1
  - Albert Fischer letter of recommendation in German
  - 1936-1938
    Scope and Contents note
    1938 June 21 Certification of passing examination in chemistry, Oct. 2, 1936 and experimental physics, Feb. 25, 1936 at German University at Prague, in German.
  - J. Klima letter of recommendation, 1938 October 27
  - Transcript or diploma?, 1938 November 2 1933 September 14
  - K. Linderstrøm-Lang letter of recommendation, 1939 July 17
  - Albert Fischer letter of recommendation, 1939 August 8
  - Appointment as Research Fellow in Medicine at Massachusetts General Hospital, Boston, Mass, 1941 August 27
  - Certificate of naturalization, 1945 January 15
  - Appointment as Research Fellow in Medicine at Harvard College, 1945 May 14
  - Certificate of literacy, 1946 October 9
  - On election to membership in American Society of Biological Chemists, 1951 May 10
  - On election to membership in The British Biochemical Society, 1952 December 22
  - Receipts for payment of membership dues to The British Biochemical Society, 1956 January 2-1961 January 3
  - On election to membership in RI chapter of the Society of the Sigma Xi, 1958 October 27
  - Announcement of Sigma Xi initiation ceremony, banquet, lecture, 1958 October 27
  - On Sigma Xi annual dues payment, 1958 October 27
  - The Society of Sigma Xi membership certificate, 1958 November 25
  - Certificate of welcome as contributor to the Encyclopedia Britannica, 1959 March 10
  - Certificate of National Honorary membership in Iota Sigma Pi, 1969 June 8
    Includes 2 items correspondence Oct. 17, 29 concerning National honorary membership.
- Obituary material (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - RU press release; RU announcement
  - New York Times, 1974 September 10
  - Nature 251, 1974; 363 items
  - News and Notes 6, 1974 October; 3 items
  - Rehovoth, Israel Biochemical Society meeting, Session on Enzymes I. In memory of G.E. Perlmann. Program, 1975 March 17
  - Letters received during illness and after death. Replies written after death., 14 letters
    Related Materials
    [See Box 3, Folder 8 The Iotan Newsletter for addt'l obits]
- Photographs, plaque, mementos (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Photographs (some duplicates), 1940 1947-1973
    Includes: Group photograph of MacInnes laboratory with identification - 3 copies - taken in middle 1940's.
    - Assorted personal photographs; scientists; friends, laboratory; some identified and dated
    - Memento; cartoon
    - Linderstrøm-Lang honorary plaque
      [see also Garvan Award]
- Garvan Award, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Biographical/Historical note
  In 1965 Dr. Perlmann received the Garvan Award.
  Awarded by American Chemical Society in recognition of distinguished service to chemistry by women chemists.
  Folder includes the following.
  - Award announcements
    - first announcement of award, 1965 August 31
    - received award, 1965 April 5
  - Letters of congratulations
  - Garvan medal
  - Chemical and Engineering News award announcement, 1964 September 7
  - Chemical and Engineering News award announcement and biographical sketch, 1965 April 12
  - Atlantic City, N.J. 150th ACS meeting. Garvan medal symposium. Delivers Garvan Award lecture "Anatomy of a protein molecule", 1965 September 14
    Includes typescript of lecture; photographic prints of what appears to be slides in lecture.
- Notes of appreciation from RU students for assistance on degree completion (Box 1, Folder 6)
  [Editor's note: Removed page from student thesis containing note].
  Arrangement
  - David L. Eaker, 1962
  - Lewis Joel Greene, 1962
  - Joseph A. Gally, 1964
  - Paul Englund, 1966
  - Sanford R. Simon, 1967
- Iota Sigma Pi (National Honor Society for Women in Chemistry), 1963-1966
  G.E. Perlmann served as National Vice President and Chairman of Extension Committee. She Was actively involved in sponsorship of new chapters. She worked with host chapter in making arrangements for 1966 Convention. (She was unable to attend).
  - Correspondence with President, 1963-1966 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence with National Council, 1962 1963-1966 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence with National Council; others, 1967-1973 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Extension Committee (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Includes ACS pamphlet "Minimum standards used as criteria in evaluating under graduate professional training in chemistry".
    New or reactivated chapters include.
  - New or reactivated chapters
    - BU: Hunter College (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Fordham University (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Marion College (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - University of Houston (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Convention (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Convention Reports (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - History, constitution, various publications, handbook revisions, procedure for chapter formation and some membership lists (Box 3, Folder 2-7)
  - The Iotan Newsletter (Box 3, Folder 8)
    Copies of following issues. Also includes duplicated copies of above pages. 1982 Sept 27 Sister Mary Rose at request of Dr. Anne Sherren to RU Archives
    - No. 4, 1973 November; p. 9
      Includes Perlmann ms "Recipe for an exciting career: Hard work and a little luck".
    - No. 9, 1975 May; p. 6
      Includes G.E. Perlmann obituary.
    - No. 11, 1976 February; p. 11
      Includes announcement of memorial service for.
- Correspondence, 1944-1974
  Correspondence with some scientific colleagues reveals ties of friendship. The correspondence on a whole deals with experimental work. Indicates strong ties to Israel and friendship with Ephraim Katzir-Katchalski. Invitations and attendance to many Gordon Conferences; also American Chemical Society and Federation meetings. Had many visiting Israeli scientists working in her laboratory and made frequent visits to Israel to work at the Weizmann Institute. Dr. Perlmann's recommendations for Nobel Prize and others awards and membership to societies reveals a very generous aspect of her personality.
  Arranged in alphabetical order including incoming and outgoing letters. Number in parenthesis indicates number of items.
  - A-Al (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Academic Press, 1962-1971; 8 items
      Includes J. Feder proposal review.
    - Adams, Elijah Concerning Tom Finlay, 3 items
    - Albertson, Donna (Wilson), 23 items
      Includes recommendations for graduate school admission; NSF fellowship.
    - Albertsson, Per-Ake, 1 item
    - Alexander, Mira, 1 item
    - Allerton, Samuel E., 1960-1971; 63 items
      Deals primarily with staff appointment; phosvitin work; recommendations for; employment recommendation for Nelly Canaan; Allerton et al reprints.
    - Allfrey, Vincent G., 1 item
    - Alpers, Joseph B. Harvard Medical school talk, 1963 February 25; 2 items
    - Altschul, Aaron M., 2 items
  - Am-Ax (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - American Association of University Professors, 1969
      Dr. Perlmann becomes member; primarily duplicated material includes copy of RU chapter AAUP constitution.
    - American Chemical Society, 1965-1974; 25 items
      Deals primarily with workings as member of Award Committee for ACS in Biological Chemistry 1965 Jan.-1967 Dec. sponsored by Eli Lilly & Co. 1966, 67, 68 list of nominees and Perlmann balloting. Material marked confidential.
    - American Institute of Biological Sciences. Concerns Perlmann 1952 Oct. review of tabular data on "Molecular weights and isoelectric points of proteins" for Handbook of Biological Data, 1952 October; 6 items
    - American Institute of Chemists, 2 items
    - Anfinsen, C.B., 1 item
    - Ansari, Aftab A., 2 items
    - Antonini, E., 2 items
    - Applequist, John, 1 item
    - Appleyard, R.K., 3 items
    - Arnon, Ruth, 1960-1974; 74 items
      Includes items on staff appointment; recommendations for; trypsin work; Micky Arnon (daughter) thank you for books.
    - Arnstein, Henry V. London, King's College seminar, 1973 June 20; 5 items
    - Arvidsson, Eric O., 2 items
    - Askonas, Ita, 1 item
    - Avaeva, S., 2 items
    - Avi-Dor, Y., 2 items
    - Avidor, Yoram, 1 item
    - Avigad, Gad, 1 item
    - Axelrod, Bernard, 5 items
  - American Society of Biological Chemists, 1964 1972 1973-1974; 44 items (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Includes correspondence; reprints; bibliographies and curriculum vitaes for some.
    Concerns nominations for membership in American Society of Biological Chemists of.
    - Mary Mycek, 1964
    - H.C. Chen, 1972
    - Anne Gounaris, 1972
    - Tom Finlay, 1973-1974
    - Marina J. Gorbunoff, 1973
  - American Society of Biological Chemists, 1963-1964 1964-1965; 23 items (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Includes correspondence. as committee member and workings as chairman of committee; photocopied IUPAC report on vitamin nomenclature; 1963-1964; 1964-1965 roster of ASBC.
    - Member of Joint Committee on Biochemical nomenclature, 1962-1965
    - Chairman of Joint Committee on Biochemical nomenclature of the ASBC/AIN. Function of committee to review nomenclature proposed by IUPAC, 1965-1966
  - Bauer, Walter, 1948-1963; 75 items (Box 4, Folder 5)
    Includes Bauer holographs, 1963 Dec. Bauer Obituary issued by Massachusetts General Hospital, Boston.
  - B-Bo (Box 4, Folder 6-7)
    - Bahl, O.P. On phosvitin work, 3 items (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Bailey, J., 2 items (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Banerjee, A., 2 items (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Barany, M., 2 items (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Barrall, E.M. II, 1974; 8 items (Box 4, Folder 6)
      Includes 1974 Santa Garbara, Calif., Gordon Conference.
    - Barsky, James, 8 items (Box 4, Folder 6)
      Includes items on publishing "Collected works of Aharon Katzir-Katchalsky".
    - Bassett, E.G., 1 item (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Bauer, Henry C., 1 item (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Bauer, Shabtai. Job inquiry with curriculum vitae, 3 items (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Bearn, Alexander B., 1973-1974; 5 items (Box 4, Folder 6)
      Primarily with serving on 1973/74 Harvey Society nominating committee.
    - Bello, J. On supporting Gordon Conference on Polymer and Solvent Interactions, 1963; 2 items (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Benziman, M., 1 item (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Berg, Paul, 1 item (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Bergmann, Peter G., 1 item (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Bernhard, S.A., 1 item (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Bessman, Samuel P., 1 item (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Beychok, S., 1 item (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Beyer, R.E. Job inquiry, 9 items (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Biochemical Society, 2 items (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Birk, Yehudith, 1965-1974; 44 items (Box 4, Folder 6)
      Includes: promotion recommendation for A. Gertler; 1972 Mar., 1974. Apr. visits to Israel.
    - Bland, Nada Ciba Foundation, 15 items (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Blatchley, Judith, 1 item (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Blauer, G., 2 items (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Blomback, Birger and M. Stockholm, Karolinska Institute lecture, 1968 September 2; 15 items (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Blout, Elkan R., 1961-1970; 33 items (Box 4, Folder 6)
      Includes items on pepsin-pepsinogen work.
    - Blumenfeld, Olga O., 1956-1973; 54 items (Box 4, Folder 7)
      Includes: items on staff appointment; recommendations for; Blumenfeld reprints.
    - Blumenfeld, Y. Israel Biochemical Society membership, 2 items (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Boelsma, E., 10 items (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Bohak, Z. Primarily biographic material about E. Katchalski for possible award nomination, 6 items (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Boman, H.G., 32 items (Box 4, Folder 7)
      Includes staff appointment; Boman reprints.
    - Boyd, Elizabeth M. Concerning Jytte Muus retirement, 3 items (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Boyer, Paul D. Plans for volume on Proteolytic Enzymes - Methods in Enzymology, 3 items (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Br-Bu (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Bradbury, Howard, 2 items
    - Bradley, A.Z., 1 item
    - Bradley, D., 1 item
    - Bradshaw, Ralph A., 2 items
    - Brainin, Joseph Items on J.F. Kennedy Memorial Fellowships contribution at Weizmann Institute dinner, 5 items
    - Brandts, J., 2 items
    - Braumtzer, Gerhard Munich, Max-Planck Institut lecture, 1968 September 17; 5 items
    - Bregman, Judith, 1 item
    - Brody, M.D. Recommendation for Arthur J. Samuels, 2 items
    - Brooks, Chandler McC. post Harvey Lecture meetings, 1965 1966; 5 items
    - Brown, G.B. On inviting foreign dinner guests attending 6th International Cong. Biochem., NY City, 1964; 2 items
    - Brown, M.A. On nomination as Nat'l Vice-Pres. of Iota Sigma Pi, 2 items
    - Buchanan, J.M., 2 items
    - Burkey M., 12 items
    - Burton, Anne. Ciba Foundation, 9 items
    - Bush, C.A. Job inquiry; Bush reprints, 22 items
    - Bustin, Michael, 3 items
  - Ca-Cl (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Cahilly, Glenn M., 2 items
    - Canaan, Nelly, 2 items
      (See Allerton, S.E. correspondence. employment recommendation for Box 4).
    - Carr, Emma, 1 item
    - Carroll, William, 2 items
    - Cebra, John J., 1959-1973; 8 items
      Recommendations for: post-doctoral fellowship; Eli Lilly award; Cebra holograph.
    - Cepurneek, Carl P., 5 items
    - Chabay, Ilan, 2 items
    - Chatterjee, A.K. Job inquiry, 4 items
    - Chemical Abstracts. Concerns abstracting work for, 6 items
    - Chen, H.S.
      (See under American Society of Biological Chemists Box 4 Folder 3).
    - Chernuchin, Paul, 2 items
    - Chiao, Marie T. Staff appointment includes curriculum vitae, 16 items
    - Chien, C.W., 1 item
    - Chow, R.
      (See under Wong, R.C. correspondence.) Box 9).
    - Chowrashi, P.K. Job inquiry with curriculum vitae, 5 items
    - Ciba Foundation
      (See under correspondence.: Bland, Nadia; Burton, Ann Box 4).
    - Cinader, B., 3 items
    - Clark, E.E., 4 items
      Includes curriculum vitae.
    - Clark, R.C., 1974 May; 8 items
      Concerning phosvitin work; 1 item on Israel, Symposium on Polyamino Acids.
    - Clement, Gerald E. Concerning pepsin-pepsinogen; phosvitin work; ms with review, 1965-1969; 38 items
  - Co-Cu (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Cogin, G., 1 item
    - Cohen, E.G.D., 6 items
      1 Cohen holograph.
    - Cohen, Georges N., 1 item
    - Cohen, Waldo E. Concerning biochemical nomenclature, 4 items
    - Cole, David R., 1 item
    - Coleman, Joseph E. Promotion recommendation for George Taborsky, 2 items
    - Colowick, Sidney P. Concerning biochemical nomenclature, 2 items
    - Commonwealth Fund, 1945-1954; 38 items
      Deals primarily with correspondence. Perlmann/R. Heffron concerning Perlmann fellowship; includes Commonwealth Fund Fellowship application with Perlmann biographical material; fellowship progress reports of 1945 Nov.-1946 May; 1945 Nov.-1946 Oct.; 1946 Nov.-1947 Oct.
    - Conderman, Maria Fuld Concerning Eric Ellenbogen Memorial Fund, 2 items
    - Condliffe, Peter G., 2 items
    - Conference on Chemical Mechanisms of Enzyme Catalysis. Plans to attend but cancels, 4 items
    - Consolazio, Wm. V., 2 items
    - Cori, A.T. Staff appointment, 3 items
    - Cori, Osvaldo, 2 items
    - Craig, Lyman. Holograph, 1 item
    - Crane, Robert K. Employment recommendation for Rosie Wong, 1 item
    - CRC Handbook of Biochemistry and Molecular Biology, 11 items
      Dr. Perlmann member of Advisory Board of CRC Handbook-3rd edition. Correspondents include: B.J. Starkoff, Gerald Fasman.
    - Crestfield, Arthur M. 1972 January 17-21; 1974 January 13 Santa Barbara, California Gordon Conferences, 2 items
    - Crewther, W.G., 2 items
    - Cruickshank, Alexander M., 1 item
    - Cunningham, Lew, 2 items
    - Cutting, J.A., 2 items
  - D (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Danzis, C., 1 item
    - Davis, Bernard D., 2 items
    - Day, Harry G. On honoring Dr. Haurowitz, Indiana University on 70 birthday, 2 items
    - Dayhoff, Margaret, 4 items
    - Deamer, David W., 2 items
    - Decktor, Barbara, 2 items
    - DeLuca, Chester. Curriculum vitae, 1 item
    - Desnuelle, P. Marseille, France, Institut de Chimie Biologique Symposium on Proteolytic Enzymes seminar, 1969 June 27; 8 items
    - Determann, H., 3 items
    - Deutsch, Benjamin, 1 item
    - Deutsch, Harold, 2 items
    - Devi, Anima Job inquiry, 1 item
    - Devir, Alisa, 1 item
    - di Gaetano, Rosemary (Mrs. J. Finicia), 1 item
    - Diringer, Renata. Staff appointment; recommendation for, 29 items
    - Djurtoft, Robert, 4 items
    - Domont, Gilberto, 1 item
    - Doty, Paul, 1 item
    - Douzou, Pierre, 10 items
    - Drazin, Rae, 1 item
    - Dreyer, Wm. J., 10 items
  - E (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Eaker, David, 3 items
    - Edman, Pehr. Concerning phosphatase preparations, 3 items
    - Edsall, John T., 1961-1967; 17 items
      Includes items on pepsinogen work.
    - Egan, Richard. Concerning pepsinogen preparations, 11 items
    - Ehrenberg, Anders, 2 items
    - Ehrenpreis, Seymour, 2 items
    - Eirich, Frederick R., 5 items
    - Eisenmenger, William J., 1 item
    - Eisler, Lisbeth. Iota Sigma Pi meeting, 1963 May 4; 2 items
    - Eitingon, Mary, 1 item
    - Eli Lilley Award
      (See under: American Chemical Society correspondence.).
    - Elliot, Roger C., 2 items
    - Elson, David, 2 items
    - Engel, Estella K., 4 items
    - Engel, Jürgen written in German, 2 items
  - F (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Fahrney, David. On pepsin purification procedures, 1 item
    - Fantes, K.H. On phosvitin samples, 3 items
    - Fasman, Gerald K., 1960-1974; 40 items
      Includes items on: polymer preparations; serving on Advisory Board for new edition of Handbook of Biochemistry and Molecular Biology.
      (See also under: CRC Handbook... correspondence.) Box 2.
    - Feizi, Ten, 2 items
    - Ferry, John D., 6 items
    - Finicia, J. Mrs
      (See under: di Gaetano, Rosemary) Box 5.
    - Finlay, Thomas H., 1971-1974; 55 items
      (See also under: Box 4 American Society of Biological Chemists correspondence.) Staff appointment; recommendations for; Finlay et al reprints; Finlay curriculum vitae.
    - Fischer, Edmond H. Items on 1968 Gordon Conference on Proteins, 3 items
    - Folk, J.E., 3 items
    - Foltmann, Bent, 4 items
    - Forester, Tylee. Recommendation for Lore Henlein, 2 items
    - Forman, Leo Recommendation for, 1 item
    - Foss, John G., 1 item
    - Fox, J.L., 2 items
    - Fraenkel-Conrat, Jane, 5 items
      Items on election to National Honorary membership in Iota Sigma Pi: suggestion to nominate more women for American Chemical Society prizes and Ely Lilly Award.
    - Frattali, Victor P., 2 items
    - Fredericq, E., 2 items
    - Friden Division of The Singer Co., 1 item
    - Fruton, Joseph, 1 item
    - Fujiki, Hirota, 2 items
  - G-Go (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Gang, Heinrich, 1 item
    - Gamier, Jean, 5 items
    - Gaskin, Felicia Staff appointment; Gaskin et al reprint, 22 items
    - Gelotte, Bertil, 2 items
    - Genaux, Charles T., 2 items
    - Gerwin, Brenda, 2 items
    - Ghosh, S.B. Job inquiry; includes curriculum vitai; Ghosh et al reprints, 14 items
    - Gibbons, Barbara H., 1 item
    - Gibbons, Ian R., 3 items
    - Gibbons, J., 1 item
    - Gibbs, Julian H., 4 items
    - Gil-Av, E., 1 item
    - Gilbert, Martha, 1 item
    - Gilbert, G.A., 3 items
    - Gilsenan, James F. Recommendation for Jo-Ann F. Danzis, 2 items